start with a right triangle with sides
of length A and B and a hypotenuse of
length C
then draw an A by a square and next to
that draw a b by b square we can glue
these two squares together to form this
shape right here
inside of this shape we can fit one copy
of the triangle vertically like this and
we can fit a second copy horizontally
like this now we can take the two
triangular regions and rotate them as
pictured here the resulting shape is a c
by C Square this means that if a and b
are the legs of a right triangle and C
is the hypotenuse we can take an a by a
square and a b by b square and decompose
it to fit in a c by c squared that means
a squared plus b squared equals c
squared When A and B are the legs of a
right triangle with hypotenuse C this is
the Pythagorean theorem